Hey, greetings Luke. How you doing?
>> Good. How are you, Jeff?
>> Hey, good. Um, uh, good luck with, um,
coming to Carolina. Just wondered, uh,
>> just to get the the obvious question out
of the way, uh, what attracted you to
come here? And over the last couple
years, um, has the destination changed
for NFL players to come to Charlotte?
Um, and and the second question I have
is, uh, you have three degrees.
How has education paid off for you and
what and what do you what does it bring
to you on the field?
>> Yeah, Carolina was a enticing
destination. I mean, between the the
beautiful city of Charlotte, I've heard
so many great things about raising a
family and being there and all the
people that are around the organization
and then obviously from the football
side, right? Things are on the up. Uh
it's clear from the outside and the
inside that there's optimism around the
building and and things are looking
good.
In terms of uh degrees, yeah, I spent
six years in college, so I I took my
time and made sure I got all I could
have out of it and uh haven't had to use
too much of it yet. And hopefully I
don't have to for a little while, but um
you know, enjoy learning and enjoy being
a nerd for lack of a better word. So if
it comes down to it, I'll I'll be ready.
>> Hey, good luck this year.
>> Thanks, Jeff. Alex Zitlo.
>> Uh Luke, what are you a nerd about?
>> Uh that's a great question. I got my
mechanical engineering degree and then I
did my masters in aerospace engineering
and honestly it changes. I'm very much
love to learn something new. Uh you know
trying to learn piano right now. It's
going terribly. Uh fingers don't work.
>> Gotcha. Well, there are a lot of um
musically inclined people on the
Panthers, so I'm sure they can give you
a pointer or two. Um, you mentioned that
you were in college for six years. You
played um in throughout your football
career, you played on all sorts of
positions on the offensive line before
Liam Cohen in at Kentucky ultimately
made you a center and now it's uh what
you play today. How did that um how did
you having to learn all positions on the
offensive line impact you today?
Yeah, I think the biggest thing is
communication. You when you're in the
middle of it, it feels easy to say,
"Hey, this is where we're going. We're
doing X or Y or Z or whatever it may
be." But, uh, you know, those times in
college when they threw me out there at
tackle, you're like, "Wait a minute. I I
can't hear a thing out here." And so, I
think being in that scenario and being
outside or at guard or whatever it may
be, you learn exactly how crucial some
important communication can be.
Got it. Thanks, man.
>> David Newton.
>> Hey, Luke. David Newton, ESPN.com.
Welcome to Charlotte. Uh, wanted to ask
you, you faced this Carolina defense uh
last year without Jaylen Phillips and um
and Lloyd. So, when you look at it now,
what the pieces are adding, what can it
be?
>> Yeah. I think the one thing last year we
knew going into it from the Saints is we
knew uh the game's never really over,
right? You look at uh some of those
game-winning drives and some of those
games that the Panthers won last year in
close games, you knew that four
quarters, whole deal, it's going to be a
long game. You can't just go up and with
a lead in the first half and and call it
a day. So knowing that that defense was
going to keep them in it and the offense
was going to have a chance to win at the
end of the game, you knew that you had
to continue playing uh couldn't let up.
And I think like you said, you add Lloyd
and Phillips. I think uh you know, I
haven't played with Jaylen, but playing
with Devin, man, Devin, uh Devin doesn't
stop, right? Devin has a motor. He he uh
he's hard to sometimes you got to tell
him to, you know, slow down a little
bit, take his time because you can't you
can't coach what he's got.
And why'd you pick piano?
>> Uh, that's a great question. I wanted to
learn something and um it just felt I
don't know. That's I have no idea
actually.
>> And you said you're having trouble with
your fingers.
>> Yeah, man. You dislocate a couple of
them and they don't they don't quite uh
reach as far as they used to.
>> All right. Let us know when that gets
better. Appreciate it.
>> Yeah. Appreciate that.
>> Any Alex Zilla?
Hey, sorry, me again. Uh, what is
exciting about playing for an offense
like the one that's being um that's kind
of coming together here in Carolina and
specifically for um a quarterback like
Bryce Young.
>> Yeah, I think what's exciting is uh you
always know when you're taking the field
that you're going to score, right? The
mindset is we're going to score. We're
going to win this game. And I think
being able to play every drive like that
with that confidence and that uh you
know that swagger is important and also
fun.
>> And then specifically about Bryce Young,
what what what are your first
impressions of him if if you have any?
>> Yeah. Uh first impressions are
charismatic and a great leader. Um I've
heard, you know, a million great things
around the building about what kind of
person he is. So uh that's the first box
to check. And then after that, um, the
way he carries himself and the way he
interacts with other people is, uh,
impressive.
>> Mike Sarte.
>> Hey, Luke. Mike Salarte, Spectrum News1.
Welcome to the Panthers. Um, kind of
dovetailing off Alex's question there.
When you the things you say about Bryce,
how does that impact the offensive line
as you guys break the huddle? when
you've got a quarterback that you're
excited to play for and has the
opportunity and the ability to, you
know, move the ball down the field and
and make things exciting.
>> Yeah. I think similar, you know, the way
I said when you take the field, right,
you have that confidence and you're
feeling good about we're going to score,
we're going to win this game, etc. I
think even when you break the huddle
right in those few seconds you're
walking up there knowing all right, you
know, Bryce has got us. He's going to
make a play. Uh the offense is going to
do something explosive here. Having that
in the back of your head, uh it just
lets you play free. It lets you play
with a sense of purpose and knowing, all
right, if I do my job, good things are
going to happen.
>> And have you given any thought about the
road trip back to the dome?
>> Uh man, I love playing in the dome. So,
I'll be I'll be excited to go back.
>> Joe Parson.
>> Oh, sorry. Go ahead, Joe.
>> You even finished up, Mike.
>> Yeah, I was just I was just going to
say, I mean, how how much of an
advantage was that place for you guys as
a as a team? I know offensively it
didn't impact you guys at all, but that
kind of juice and what, you know, how do
you maybe
anticipate, you know, the Panthers crowd
lifting you guys up?
Yeah, I remember I mean playing in
Charlotte, uh I remember how beautiful
the sun was. You know, you don't get
much of that in the dome. Uh but I think
the the crowd, the fans, it like I said,
it seems like there's a sense of
optimism and it's just they just need
one little thing to one little spark to
have something to cheer for and I think
you saw a lot of that last year and I
think you're going to continue to see
that.
>> Thanks,
>> Luke. Good to see you, man. and I'm with
the athletic here in town. Hope you're
doing well.
Um, tell us a little more about these
degrees. Like, were you um, you know,
were you a nerd in high school? Were you
in the chess club? Give give us a little
peek into like high school. Luke Forner.
>> Oh man. Uh, let's see. In the middle in
middle school, I played the baritone and
I had a big decision going into freshman
year of high school. I said, "Am I going
to play in the band or play football?"
And I think I decided correctly. Uh I
know my middle school band director may
not think so, but uh you know, and then
I went into high school and um
was lucky enough that I uh could handle
the information and do well and also
balance sports. And I think um going
into college, I I definitely wanted to
play college football, but the NFL was
kind of one of those things that uh
they're like, "Well, not everyone makes
it to the NFL. you got to try and, you
know, get your education and blah blah
blah. And so I I kept hanging on with
the red shirt year and the co year and
eventually my buddies were like, "Are
you going to go, you know, are you going
to go do this? Like you have a chance to
go play in the NFL. It's it's time you
you know, put the school aside, right?
And and go take this chance." And so,
uh, owe a lot to them. And they're
still, you know, asking for money to
this day. So
>> that's awesome. Hey. Um, you were asked
about Devin a minute ago. You have any
any, you know, cool Devon stories from
your time together on or off the field?
>> Man, uh, like I, like I said, you got to
tell Devin, you know, it's practice. You
got to say, "Hey, it's it's not Sunday,
right?" Like I mean, I there's countless
times where where it's offense versus
defense, and it's hot out there, and
you're going after it, and and Devin's
just not slowing down, man. So, what
like I said, you want that as opposed to
the opposite, right? You don't want
someone you have to try and pump up on
game day. So, uh that's the one thing
that sticks out to me about Devin.
>> And then two more real quick ones. Um
did you uh you faced Derek Brown last
year when you were with New Orleans? And
what what was that like?
>> Yeah, man. He's hard to block. There's
uh you know, I'd love to sit here and
talk details and technicalities, but at
the end of the day, man, he's a he's a
hard dude to block. And like I said,
he's part of that defense that, you
know, they're never going to quit. Um,
and then after I' I've gotten here, I've
just heard great things about him.
>> And then lastly, you were in Kenny
Pickicket's draft class, too. Do you
have any background with him at all? Did
you meet him at pre-draft or anything?
>> No, I never met him, but uh, you know,
in the NFL, you're always one degree of
separation away, and everyone I've
talked to has high praise for him, and
uh, excited to get to work with him.
>> Luke, thanks very much. Appreciate it.
>> We have time for a few more. We'll go
with Vashai.
>> Hi Luke. Sorry I can't turn on my
camera, but I will meet you in person
when you come to Charlotte. Um I'm f I'm
c curious what your familiarity
familiarity is with some of the guys
you'll be playing along the line with.
Rob Hunt, Damen Lewis. Um so yeah.
>> Yeah. I've you know haven't had the
chance to to meet any of them or or do
anything of that sort. And it's funny. I
feel like I know a lot of people a lot
of places, but Carolina is one of the
places I hadn't met anyone. Uh, so I
know from their tape and from what I've
seen on tape, uh, impressive, right? And
I think that was one of the selling
points and one of the reasons I chose to
be here was to play around really good
players.
>> Thanks.
>> Any more questions for Luke?
>> All right, Luke. Thank you. I want I
want to ask what what band instrument do
you play when you in a band?
>> Uh the baritone. It's like a mini tuba.
>> And why did you give that up? I mean
>> that it was you know I wasn't going to
do the there was a couple people who did
it where they went to football practice
and then they went to band camp or vice
versa. I can't remember. But I said I'm
gonna I'm gonna do one of these things
out outside in the summer and and
probably not both.
>> Okay.
>> Did you face Bryce at all in college?
Man, I know you were on the same side of
the ball, but y'all were y'all didn't
overlap at all.
>> I don't think so. No.
>> Okay. Thanks.
>> All right, Luke, that seems to be all
the questions we have. Thank you so much
for taking the time this morning.
>> Thank you guys. Meet you all soon.